A farewell to Westeros with the people who built the realm
Game of Thrones: The Last Watch is a documentary film directed by Jeanie Finlay.
For a year, acclaimed British filmmaker Jeanie Finlay was embedded on the set of the hit HBO series “Game
of Thrones,” chronicling the creation of the show’s most ambitious and complicated season.
Debuting one week after the series 8 finale, GAME OF THRONES: THE LAST WATCH delves deep into the mud and blood to reveal the tears and triumphs involved
in the challenge of bringing the fantasy world of Westeros to life in the very real studios, fields and car-parks of Northern Ireland.
Made with unprecedented access, GAME OF THRONES: THE LAST WATCH is an up-close and personal portrait from the trenches of production, following
the crew and the cast as they contend with extreme weather, punishing deadlines and an ever-excited fandom hungry for spoilers.
Much more than a “making of” documentary, this is a funny, heartbreaking story, told with wit and intimacy, about
the bittersweet pleasures of what it means to create a world – and then have to say goodbye to it.
Self, played by Lena Headey.
Self, played by Emilia Clarke.
Self, played by Kit Harington.
Self, played by Nikolaj Coster-Waldau.
Self, played by Peter Dinklage.
Self, played by Sophie Turner.
Game of Thrones: The Last Watch is a 2019 documentary film that chronicles the production of the
eighth and final season of HBO's medieval fantasy television series Game of Thrones.
It was directed by Jeanie Finlay and aired on HBO on May 26, 2019,
one week after the series finale of Game of Thrones.
The documentary details Finlay's experience on the set of the show over the course of a
year, spanning from the first table read to the filming of the final scene.
Described by HBO as revealing "the tears and triumphs involved in the challenge of bringing the fantasy world of Westeros to life", the film features behind-the-scenes
footage and interviews with prominent actors and writers, as well as production assistants, costume designers, set decorators, caterers, and carpenters.
Game of Thrones: The Last Watch received mostly
positive reviews from critics and audiences.
It was nominated for Outstanding Music Composition for a
Documentary Series at the Primetime Emmy Awards.
The film explores themes of behind the scenes, filmmaking,
making of, documentary filmmaking, creative process.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking.